

HARSHIT SHARMA

OBJECTIVE

10+years of experience in the field of Accounts & Export Documentation. Well knowledge of Computers, Seeking a challenging position in my field of experience, in a competitive and growth oriented environment. Now I am waiting for the better opportunities and higher responsibility for the betterment of my carrier.

EXPERIENCE

R.P. Locks Co. (Harrison Locks.) – Export/Import Executive Aligarh, India 04/2024-Current

- · Coordination and communications with buyers
- Shipping line / airline coordination and documentation for activities in imports, carrier invoice, payment to the carrier, carrier delivery order.
- Raise invoice to the customer on time & payment to be followed up.

Vestal Manufacturers & Traders – Export Executive (Export House) Aligarh, India 01/2022 - 03/2024

- Coordinate and manage all aspects of the export process, including documentation, customs clearance, and shipment scheduling.
- Communicate with international clients, freight forwarders, and customs agents to ensure timely delivery of goods.
- Prepare and review export documents, such as invoices, packing lists, and proforma invoice, with regulatory requirements.
- Maintain accurate records of shipments, including tracking information and customs documentation.
- Maintaining record duty drawbacks & preparation of RODTEP/related incentives
- Reviews and approves all export transactions- end user end check and update BRC's through DGFT
- Use country of destination. Manages any issues including third party's payments.
- Work closely with service providers to gather shipments details resolve problem or streamline processes.

Feedpro Hatcheries And Farms Pvt.Ltd-Accounts Executive

Aligarh, India

06/2021 -01/2022

- Post business transactions, process invoices, verify financial data for use in maintaining accounts payable records
- Clarify any questionable invoice items, prices or receiving signatures
- Maintain copies of vouchers, invoices or correspondence necessary for files
- Obtain proper information and/or data regarding invoice payments
- Reconcile bank statements
- Input daily bookkeeping and record keeping
- Verify invoices against purchase orders and ensure goods or services were received before issuing payment to vendors
- Processing of payments and financial transactions to suppliers and obtaining goods and services from suppliers promptly
- · Preparing cheques for payment

Ganga Handicrafts (Export House) - Export Executive & Financial Analyst Moradabad, India

Digvijay Exports (Export House) - Accountant Moradabad, India 01/2012-04/2018

- Voucher entry ensuring invoices are accurate and per purchasing documents
- Payment processing preparing weekly payment batches accurately and timely and ensuring all payments are in accordance with purchasing policies and procedures.
- Updating, when necessary, vendor, merchant and/or vendor account information.
- Prepare and audit export documentation for vessel shipments and settlements
- Submit timely document instructions to freight forwarders, independent surveyors and other third-party industry providers
- Verify sanctioned party screenings prior to release of export documents
- Proof of documents submission to bank.
- Booking of international courier of sample consignments.
- Co-ordination with shipping agents for arrangements of exports/import FCL, LCL & AIR shipments.

SKILLS

EDUCATION

Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP) LL. B:

General Ledger Updates Ability to multi-task & manage Moradabad time efficiently.

Ability to grasp and learn new 06/2013 things quickly.

Ability to be flexible & work in Moradabad accordance with organization

Tally ERP/Busy/SAP

Gmail & Outlook

Creative Response

11/2019 (2016)

Sales Tax & Income Tax From MJPRU

B.COM: Finance and Taxation From MJPRU

02/2012

CIA+: From The Institute Of Computer Accountant, Kolkata

Modules- BCA/FOA/TALLY/TDS/BUSY/INCOME TAX/APA/IMPORT AND EXPORT MANAGEMENT/BANKING, ROC AND LABOUR LAWS/IPM,

SHARE MARKET & PORTFOLIO MANAGEMENT

Moradabad

06/2010

12Th: Commerce

D.S Inter College Aligarh Uttar Pradesh

05/2008 10Th:

G.D Public School Aligarh Uttar Pradesh

HOBBIES

- Tracking And travelling.
- Playing indoor and outdoor games.







H NO. 10 A.D.A BRIJ VIHAR **COLONY GT ROAD ALIGARH U.P -202001 (INDIA)**

HARSHU7767@GMAIL.COM DOB: 10/09/1991

+91-9457944596